（愛花）いきなり
飛び起きないでください。→
Please don't wake so suddenly like that.
びっくりするじゃないですか。
You startled me.
愛…　花？
悪い夢でも見たんですか？
Aika...
Did you have a bad dream?
（心の声）≪どうして　愛花が？≫
Why is Aika here?
≪愛花は…≫
Aika is...
Are you still out of it?
（愛花）まだ寝ぼけてます？
I guess this is a dream...
これは　夢…　か？
（愛花）「我々は　夢と同じ糸で
織り上げられている→
We are such stuff as dreams are made on.
ささやかな一生を
しめくくるのは→
And our little life is rounded with a sleep.
眠りなのだ」。
嫌な夢を
見たのなら→
If you just had a nightmare, why not go back to sleep?
寝直してみては？
「テンペスト」か。
（愛花）あら　読んだのですか？
The Tempest, huh?
Oh, have you read it?
I read it so that I could criticize it.
じゃないと　批評できねぇからな。
（愛花）やっぱり　まめですね。
Meticulous as always.
それも復讐劇だろ。
It's another story of revenge, isn't it?
だったら　悲劇で終わらなきゃ
おかしいじゃねぇか。
Then it must end in tragedy.
悲しみは悲しみでしか
打ち消すことができない。
Only sadness can counter sadness.
だとしたら　残される者も
悲しみでしかねぇだろ。
In that case, all that's left is sadness.
「ああ　苦しくてたまらない」。
はぁ…。
O! I have suffered
with those that I saw suffer.
「あんなに
苦しむ人たちを見ていると！→
素晴らしい船→
A brave vessel
who had, no doubt, some noble creature in her
きっと立派な人たちが
乗っていたのだわ→
dashed all to pieces.
それが粉々に砕けて」。
Episode 13
The Reason of Dreams
≪そう　これは復讐劇だ≫
That's right...
This is a story of revenge.
≪悲劇を悲劇のまま
終わらせるための復讐劇≫
A story of revenge, so we can end sadness with sadness.
≫（滝川吉野）本当に　そうかな？
You really think so?
ああ？
真広→
Mahiro...
君は　悲劇で終わらせるために
あの旅をしていたの？
Did you make this journey just to end it in tragedy?
旅？
Journey?
忘れたの？
Did you forget?
That's right.
≪そうだ→
俺は　こいつと旅を…≫
I was on a journey with him.
あれは
世界を救う旅だったんじゃないの？
Didn't we journey so we could save the world?
I will save the world!
（ナレーション）＜俺が世界を？＞
The world?
＜　そんな大それたもんじゃない＞
No, nothing so ambitious.
If it saved the world, it would've been the result of something else.
＜　それは
あくまで　ついでだったはず＞
((吉野
どうして　愛花は殺された？))
Yoshino, why did Aika have to die?
It's absurd!
((くっ…　辻褄が合わない))
It doesn't make sense...
＜　そうだ　俺は愛花を…→
That's right.
My little sister, Aika, was killed.
妹を殺された＞
((どんな手を使っても
辻褄を合わせてやる))
I'll do whatever it takes for everything to make sense again!
I vowed to find the killer,
＜必ず
犯人を捜し当てると誓った＞
＜　だが　それが　世界を救うことと
どうつながる？＞
but does that relate to saving the world?
（葉風・通信）((おい　真広
これは　公平な取り引きだ。→
Hey, Mahiro...
This is a fair trade.
恩を着せられる筋合いはない))
You have no right to imply that I owe you any favors.
((そうは言っても　葉風
俺がいなくて困るのは→
You say that, Hakaze,
but you're the one in trouble without me...
（通信）お前だろ))
（葉風）((ほう。→
Oh?
貴様の妹を殺した犯人を→
Are you saying you no longer need me
私が見つけてやらなくても
いいというのか？))
to locate your sister's killer?
＜葉風＞
Hakaze...
＜鎖部葉風＞
Kusaribe Hakaze.
＜　はじまりの樹の加護を受ける
魔法使い→
The one protected by the Tree of Genesis,
鎖部一族の姫君＞
and princess of the Kusaribe.
＜　だが　ある日　樽詰めにされ→
But one day, she was stuffed in a barrel and stranded on that island.
島へ置き去りにされてしまう＞
＜　そこで葉風は　孤島から
外部へ連絡を取るため→
To contact the outside world from the island,
魔法を込めた人形を瓶に詰めて
海へ流した＞
she set adrift a magic doll sealed in a bottle.
＜　それを　俺が拾ったんだ＞
And I happened to pick it up.
＜俺は
魔法使いと取り引きをした＞
I made a deal with a mage.
＜　かつて　この世を
破壊しようとした絶園の樹は→
The Tree of Exodus once tried to destroy the world,
はじまりの樹に敗れ
その身を封じられた＞
but it lost to the Tree of Genesis and was torn apart and sealed away.
＜　一方で
はじまりの樹も深く傷つき→
However, the Tree of Genesis was also badly damaged,
今は　再生のために眠っている＞
so it sleeps, waiting to recover, even as it supports this world.
＜鎖部一族の役目は
はじまりの樹が→
The Kusaribe clan's duty
is to prevent the Tree of Exodus from reviving
再生するときまで
絶園の樹復活を抑えること＞
before the Tree of Genesis awakens.
Return! Return! Return!
＜　だが　一族の代表　鎖部左門は→
However, the leader of the Kusaribe, Kusaribe Samon,
破壊の権化
絶園の樹の復活をもくろんだ＞
planned to revive the Tree of Exodus instead.
Apparently, only the princess opposed that plan,
＜葉風だけが　それに抗ったため→
一族から
追いやられることになったという＞
and so, she was forced out of the clan.
To revive the Tree of Exodus,
＜絶園の樹の復活には→
it was necessary to gather all the fruits scattered throughout Japan.
日本中に散らばる果実を
集める必要があったが…＞
＜　それには
多くの犠牲を伴った＞
That caused many victims.
The phenomenon that occurred wherever a fruit showed up,
＜果実出現の際に発生する
呪的現象→
the Black Iron Syndrome.
それが　黒鉄病と呼ばれるものだ＞
＜多くの町や村が壊滅した＞
Cities fell and people died.
＜　だが　そんなことは
どうでもよかった＞
But I didn't really care about any of that.
＜俺は　葉風と取り引きしたんだ＞
I made a deal with Hakaze.
I would help her,
＜俺は　葉風に手を貸して→
そのかわり　愛花を殺した犯人を→
and in return, she would use magic to find Aika's killer.
魔法とやらで見つけろと＞
I've already waited a year
((俺は　もう　１年待ってる→
to kill Aika's murderer with my own hands!
愛花を殺したヤツを
この手で殺すのをな))
＜　そう　魔法使いに手を貸して
世界を救ってやる…→
Indeed...
I was helping a mage and saving the world.
そんなのは　ついでだ＞
But it just happened to coincide with my main goal.
((町は　じき封鎖される。
早く逃げろ))
The city will be quarantined soon.
You should hurry up and run.
＜滝川吉野＞
Takigawa Yoshino,
someone I'd shared an ill-fated friendship with since childhood.
＜ガキのころからの
腐れ縁だったが→
俺は　ここで
こいつと別れるつもりだった＞
I meant to say goodbye to him there.
((じゃあな))
Well, see ya!
I'll be back after I've killed Aika's murderer.
((愛花を殺したヤツをぶっ殺したら
戻ってくる))
((そのとき　彼女に会わせろ))
Introduce me to your girlfriend then.
((そうだな))
Sure.
((そのときは
ちゃんと彼女を紹介するよ))
When that happens,
I'll introduce you to her.
＜　なのに　あいつは…＞
And yet...
((おっ　助かる。　えっ？))
Oh, thanks...
Yoshino?!
((お前　バカか!?))
The hell? Are you stupid?
((俺につきあう義理はないって
言っただろ！))
I said you didn't have to stay with me!
((それがさ→
Well, you see...
友達を大事にしない人は
嫌いですって→
I imagined my girlfriend scolding me and saying,
"I dislike people who aren't good to their friends."
彼女に怒られそうでね))
Pathetic.
((情けねぇな))
＜　こうして
俺と吉野の旅は始まった＞
And so, my journey with Yoshino began.
((≫魔法使いは　直接
倒さなきゃならないだろ))
We should fight the mages head-on.
((どういうことだ？))
((お前と別れたあと→
What are you talking about?
After you left,
葉風の魔法で　愛花を殺した野郎が
かなり絞れた))
we managed to use Hakaze's magic to shorten the list of suspects.
((犯人は　鎖部一族の誰かだ))
The killer is
someone from the Kusaribe clan.
The spear guy?
（哲馬）((槍男…　ふっ。→
夏村のことか))
You mean Natsumura?
Tell me your name, mage.
（山本）
((名前を聞かせて　魔法使い))
I do not have a name
（夏村）
((覚えてもらうほどの名前は→
important enough for you to remember.
持ち合わせていない！))
The Kusaribe clan can borrow power from the Tree of Genesis
＜鎖部一族の者は
はじまりの樹の理を借り受け→
魔法を使うことができる＞
to use magic.
Very well, Princess.
（左門）((ならば　姫様
今日で　その運　尽きさせましょう))
Today, let us put an end to your good fortune.
((左門
パンツ一丁でも　私は手ごわいぞ))
Samon,
even in my underwear, I'm still pretty tough.
＜　その　はじまりの樹の加護を
一身に受ける最強の魔法使い→
The powerful mage who receives the utmost protection
from the Tree of Genesis, Kusaribe Hakaze.
鎖部葉風＞
＜　はじまりの樹の理は
葉風の理だ＞
Her reasoning is the Tree of Genesis's reasoning.
＜　あいつが何かを願えば
樹が　すべて　かなえてしまう＞
If she wishes for it, the Tree of Genesis will grant it.
If everything is going as Hakaze and the Tree of Genesis planned...
＜　すべてが
はじまりの樹と葉風の→
思いどおりに
進んでいるとしたら？＞
((行くぞ))
Let's go.
((ボゥン　ボゥン　ボゥン！))
((バシューー！))
（左門）((よく来た　少年))
Welcome, young men.
＜国防軍が絶園の樹に対して
総攻撃をかけるなか→
While the army was fighting the Tree of Exodus,
we were facing Samon.
俺たちは
鎖部左門と対峙していた＞
（葉風・通信）((久しいな　左門。→
It's been a while, Samon.
Four months now?
４か月ぶりになるか。
変わりなくやっているようだな))
Seems you're doing well.
((ふっ　姫様こそ→
You, too, Princess,
（通信）遠く隔たっていても
お変わりなく))
despite being so far away.
＜葉風が用意していた
特製の魔具を持って→
With that powerful talisman Hakaze made,
俺たちが　この地に来た時点で
勝敗は決していたはずだったが…＞
our victory should have been guaranteed
the moment we arrived, but...
Samon told us that it was actually the Tree of Genesis,
＜絶園の樹ではなく→
はじまりの樹が　むしろ
世界を滅ぼすかもしれないと→
and not the Tree of Exodus, that would destroy the world.
左門は言った＞
But I actually don't give a crap.
＜　だが　俺には
そんなことは　どうでもいい＞
((世界の心配は　あとだ))
I'll worry about the world later.
Now, get Hakaze back...
((さあ　葉風を戻せよ))
That's right.
＜　そうだ
世界を救うなんて　二の次だ＞
Saving the world comes later!
((俺は　あいつに
見つけてもらうヤツがいる))
There's someone she needs to find for me!
＜　なのに…＞
Yet...
((姫様　今は何年です？))
Princess, what year is it?
((今は　西暦…))
Right now, it's...
＜鎖部の姫君は→
The princess was trapped in the time prison two years ago.
２年前の時間の檻に
封じ込められていた＞
＜今現在は　骨になってるんなら
ここへは　戻りようがない＞
If she was already a bunch of bones, bringing her back was pointless.
＜葉風との契約も
ここまでだった＞
And my deal with Hakaze would end here.
((残念だったな　葉風))
Too bad, Hakaze.
((まあ　骨になってるんなら
しかたねぇ))
Well, there's nothing we can do if you're just bones.
((そこで勝手に死んでろ))
Yeah, just die there.
＜　だったら
取り引き相手を変えるだけだ＞
Then I merely need to deal with someone else.
＜愛花を殺した犯人が分かれば
それでいいからな＞
Because all that matters to me is finding Aika's killer.
((分かった。
お前の要求に応じよう))
Very well.
I will grant your wish.
＜　これで
取り引き成立のはずだったが…＞
The deal should have been sealed, but...
I'm sorry, Mahiro.
((ごめん　真広))
The hell are you doing?!
((ちょっと　その魔具を
渡してもらおうと思ってね！))
Thought I'd borrow that talisman for a sec.
((真広
こちらの側につくというなら→
Mahiro, if you'll switch back to this side,
お前に　愛花ちゃんの彼氏が
誰だったか教えてやる))
I'll tell you the identity of Aika's boyfriend.
＜吉野が　愛花の彼氏が
誰だか知ってると→
Yoshino suddenly said he knew who Aika's boyfriend was.
ぬかしやがった＞
You really know who it was?
((ああ　知ってる。　でも真広→
Yes, I know.
But, Mahiro,
僕の話に乗らないかぎり→
unless you agree to my terms,
誰かは　一生　教えない))
I will never tell you who it was.
((お前は　誰か知らないまま
一生　悩むことになるぞ))
You'll be left ignorant of who it was forever.
I won't agree that easily.
＜　それは　ごめんだ＞
＜吉野のヤツ　とんでもない
奥の手を隠し持ってたわけだ＞
Damn it, Yoshino.
He was holding the ultimate trump card.
＜何を思ったか→
I don't know what he was thinking,
吉野は　葉風をここに戻すことが
可能だと立証するために→
but to prove the fact that it was possible to bring Hakaze back,
熱弁を振るいだした＞
he started a debate.
＜　でたらめな論理だったが→
Even though his logic was weak...
へこんだお姫様を
奮い立たせるには十分だったろう＞
it was enough to lift the depressed princess's spirits.
（哲馬・通信）((左門殿→
Mr. Samon.
１年前に殺人を犯した者の調査が
終わりました))
We've concluded the investigation into the murder a year ago by one in the clan.
((そうか！
犯人が特定できたか！))
I see.
So you've found the murderer!
＜　だが　ここまでだ＞
But that's the end of the line.
＜犯人が分かれば
葉風が戻る戻らないは関係ない＞
If I learn who killed Aika,
it doesn't matter to me whether Hakaze is here or not.
（哲馬・通信）((それが左門殿…→
However, Mr. Samon...
The killer is not in the clan!
犯人は　一族内にいないのです！))
((いるかもしれん))
There may be
((いるかもしれんのだ…→
one person who could have escaped the web of magic!
ただ一人
魔法の網にかからぬ者が！))
((いや　破壊こそが理の者が！))
No, someone whose logic is destruction itself.
((いわば　絶園の魔法使いが！))
In other words... the mage of Exodus!
＜絶園の樹は　この世で唯一→
The Tree of Exodus is the only one
はじまりの樹の理を
超える力を持つ＞
with power that can surpass the Tree of Genesis.
＜愛花は　その絶園の魔法使いに
殺されたのか？＞
Did this mage of Exodus kill Aika?
＜　それとも
俺と葉風を結び付けるために→
Or was she killed by the Tree of Genesis,
はじまりの樹によって
殺されたのか？＞
in order to bring Hakaze and me together?
((たとえ
本当に　はじまりの樹が→
Even if the Tree of Genesis really did cause Mahiro's sister's death,
真広の妹の死を
招いたのだとしても→
I must go back there!
私は　そちらに戻らねばならん))
((戻らねば　何もできん。
何も償えん))
I can do nothing until I'm back!
I cannot make any amends...
＜　どちらにせよ　まずは
葉風が時間の檻を破って→
No matter how things go,
if Hakaze doesn't break free from the prison of time,
ここへ戻ってこないと
話は進まない＞
nothing will happen.
Only after that will we be able to determine the killer's identity.
＜誰が犯人か決めるのは
それからだ＞
（葉風）((我が名は　鎖部葉風))
I am Kusaribe Hakaze,
the Princess of Genesis.
((はじまりの姫宮))
((２年の時を越え　帰って来たぞ))
I've traveled two years through time to return.
これは…。
≫思い出した？
This is...
Do you remember now?
俺は…。　俺とお前は　このあと…。
I...
You and I...
Yoshino!
（葉風）((はぁ　はぁ　はぁ))
((吉野!!))
Yoshino!
Don't go!
行かないで！
やっぱり　俺は死んだんだな…。
So I really did die...
（愛花の声）あら　まだですよ。
Oh, not yet.
だから　何を言って…。
What the hell are you saying?!
（愛花の声）
真広も言っていたでしょう。
You said it yourself, Mahiro.
この物語は
悲劇では終わらないんです。
This story doesn't end in tragedy.
また夢か…。
Am I
dreaming again?
吉…　野？
Yoshino?
やあ。
やあじゃねぇよ！　彼氏は!?
Hey!
Don't "Hey" me! Who is it?
愛花の彼氏は誰なんだ!?
Who was Aika's boyfriend?
あのあと　どうなったか知りたい？
Don't you want to know what happened next?
あのあと？
Next?
死んだよ。　みんな死んじゃった。
They died.
They all died.
はじまりの樹が
全部　飲み込んじゃったんだ。
The Tree of Genesis swallowed them all up.
はじまりの樹は　世界中に現れて→
The Tree of Genesis appeared across the world,
and swallowed up all the cities and the people.
町も人も飲み込んじゃった。
Armies, worldwide, went to fight it.
だから
世界中の軍隊が反撃に出たんだ。
But none of them returned.
でも　みんな帰って来なかった。
はじまりの樹に
吸収されちまったのか？
Did the Tree of Genesis absorb them?
立ち向かうものは
みんな飲み込まれちゃった。
Anything that opposed it was swallowed up.
６０億－２０億は？
What's six billion minus two billion?
ああ？　４０億だろ？
Four billion...
That is the current world population.
それが今の全世界の人口。
あっ…。
たった数時間で　たくさん壊されて
たくさん殺されたんだ。
Many places were destroyed, and many people were killed
in a matter of hours.
そりゃ　後片づけが大変そうだな。
Sounds like cleaning that up would suck.
死んだ人も残されたものも
みんな消えちゃった。
The dead have all vanished, along with anything left behind.
The Tree ate them all.
全部　樹に食べられちゃった。
食べられたのは　はじまりの樹を
攻撃したものばかりじゃないんだ。
But the ones the Tree ate weren't limited to those who attacked it.
紛争中の地域とか
暴動が起こっている所にも→
It appeared in areas affected by hardship and rebellion, as well.
樹は出現した。
町なかでも　戦闘行為があれば→
Even in cities with mere intentions of war,
それを察知して
はじまりの樹が出てくるんだ。
the Tree of Genesis sensed that fact and appeared.
だから　誰も戦争をしなくなった。
So no one starts wars anymore.
樹は
小さな犯罪も見ているらしいんだ。
The Tree also seems to monitor minor crime.
略奪や暴動を起こしても
樹は現れる。
It appears to robbers and rebels, too.
If we started fighting, it could appear before us.
ここで　僕と真広がケンカしても
出てくるかもしれないよ。
今　世界は　すごく平和なんだ。
The world is very peaceful now.
ん？
お土産。　コンビニで買ってきた。
Gifts...
I got them at the convenience store.
あれから７日くらいでね
買えるようになったんだ。
It took around seven days to be able to buy these again.
Water and electricity were restored, too.
止まってた電気や水道も
復旧したんだよ。
結構なことじゃねぇか。
Actually, that sounds pretty good.
それだけじゃない。　見て。
ん？
That isn't all.
Look.
これは？
これも　世界中で見られる現象。
What's that?
It's a worldwide phenomenon.
Deserts turned into forests,
砂漠は森になったし→
and polluted seas returned to normal.
汚かった海も
元どおりに戻っていってる。
Because of that,
だから　水不足や食料問題まで
解決しちゃいそうなんだ。
we're on the brink of resolving food and water shortages in the world.
なんだ　そりゃ。
はじまりの樹様様じゃねぇか。
What the hell...
Sounds like we should be
praising the Tree of Genesis.
あれから　絶園の樹も
動かなくなっちゃった。
The Tree of Exodus stopped moving afterwards, too.
There aren't any fruits in sight, either.
果実も　一つも飛んでないよ。
不合理だな。
えっ？
It's irrational.
Huh?
The world has been saved without my help,
世界は　勝手に救われたが→
but things still don't make any sense to me.
これじゃ　俺の辻褄が合わない。
やっぱり
悲劇は悲劇で終わらせたい？
So you really do want to end a tragedy with a tragedy?
復讐を遂げないと終わらない？
You won't be satisfied unless you get your revenge?
俺は…。
I...
That's right.
＜　そうだ　俺は愛花の…＞
I need to find Aika's...
((ちっ。　また愛花のお小言を
聞かなきゃならねぇのか))
Do I really have to listen to Aika talk crazy again?
((愛…　花？　はぁ～))
Aika...
((何やってんだよ　お前
こんなとこで…))
What the hell are you doing?
＜誰が信じられるだろう＞
Who would have believed the sight
＜彼女に咲いた赤い花＞
of the red flower that bloomed from her?
＜　こんなにも冷たい　その肌＞
Her skin felt so cold...
＜　それでも分からなかった→
And yet, I couldn't believe that Aika was dead.
これで
愛花が死んでいるだなんて＞
＜　なぜなら…＞
Why?
＜俺は知らない＞
While Aika was alive,
＜命ある愛花→
I never knew...
その肌の柔らかさを　ぬくもりを→
The softness of her skin, her warmth.
俺は　一度だって知らない＞
はぁ～。
≪ガチャ（ドアの音）
悪い夢でも見たか？
Did you have a bad dream?
Samon, huh?
左門か。
寝覚めに見るには最悪なツラだな。
You're probably the worst face to see when waking up.
開口一番　それか。
So that's the first thing you say?
How long was I asleep?
どのくらい　俺は寝てた？
（左門）約１か月だ。→
About a month.
もっと早く起こせもしたが
状況が状況だけにな→
I could have woken you earlier,
but circumstances are as they are.
魔法の効果で　しばらく
寝たままでいてもらった。→
I had you stay asleep with magic.
Don't hate me.
悪く思うな。
ん…。
はじまりの樹か。
（左門）ああ　その一部だ。
Is that the Tree of Genesis?
A portion of it, yes.
何も聞かないんだな。
Don't you have anything to ask?
夢で見たとおりだ。　はっ…。
It's just like my dream.
吉野は!?　吉野は無事か!?
Where's Yoshino? Is he safe?!
He's acting separately, but don't worry.
（左門）我らと別行動ではあるが
心配ない。→
お前より健康で
お前より頭が回っている。
He's much more healthy and intelligent than you.
Is that right?
そうかよ。
で　なんで　俺を生かした。
Well? Why'd you keep me alive?
俺に何をさせたい。
What do you want from me?
（左門）不破真広→
Fuwa Mahiro,
お前は　滝川吉野を殺せるか？
could you kill Takigawa Yoshino?
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
（羽村）オーライ　オーライ。→
Good, good...
ストップ。→
Stop.
オッケーです。　ふぅ…。
That's fine.
≪（同僚）
羽村さ～ん　休憩ですよ～。→
Hanemura, it's lunchtime!
彼女に振られた!?
Your girlfriend dumped you?!
（羽村）将来性のない
頼りない人なんかいらないって。
She said she didn't want someone so irresponsible, without a future...
That's harsh.
えぐいですね。
はぁ…。
あっ　話は変わるんですけど
絶園の魔法使いのうわさって→
Oh, on a different subject...
Have you heard the rumor about the mage of Exodus?
聞いたことあります？
あっ…。
（同僚）
なんでも　あの樹を壊して→
They say one exists and might be able to destroy that Tree, and return everything to normal?
世界を元どおりにできる
魔法使いが→
いるとか　いないとか…。
（羽村）
ああ　それ　たぶん　僕のことだ。
Oh, they're probably talking about me.
へえ～。　はっ？
Oh...
Huh?
（羽村）世界を救ったら→
If I saved the world,
you think I'd have a future?
僕にも　将来性　出てくるかな…。
Hakaze has a crush on Yoshino?!
葉風が吉野にほれた!?
I hear that he has a girlfriend!
（葉風）聞けば　あやつ
彼女もいるというではないか。
（左門）今や姫様は→
All of the princess' thoughts revolve around Takigawa Yoshino.
滝川吉野を中心に
物事を考えているのだ。
（葉風）私の知ったことか！
はぁ～。　つまり…。
Like I care?!
Meaning...
（左門）滝川吉野が
絶園の魔法使いである可能性に。
Takigawa Yoshino may be the mage of Exodus.
（葉風）いつ　その力に気付いた？
When did you realize this power?
まあ　しかたありませんか。
I guess there's no other choice...
Episode 14
Happy New Year